Oh, the sacred spirit of the mountains and rivers, 4,000 years of
Ôi hồn thiêng sông núi 4 ngàn năm xử
golden age still calls the names of those who fell so that the
vàng vẫn gọi tên các anh nằm xuống để
Nation could rise up. Motherland opens her arms to embrace
Đất Nước Đứng Lên đất mẹ dang tay ôm
you forever. Your elderly mother and young children are left
trọn anh mãi mãi mẹ già con thơ anh để
behind in the country, living out their loyalty and affection.
lại đất nước thay anh sống trọn nghĩa
Those living in peacetime
tình những con người sống giữa thời bình
will continue to write the story of your bright youth. Oh,
sẽ viết tiếp thanh xuân anh sáng giờ Ôi
growing up
lớn lên
[music]
[âm nhạc]
for the homeland,
vì quê hương
not knowing how far,
chẳng biết bao xa
I vow for it, even though I
nguyện vì trong xe
know that
dẫu biết rằng
vows have changed.
nguyện cũng đã thay
[music]
[âm nhạc]
Every homeland, I am so
từng quê hương tôi
grateful to the
ơn biết mấy
soldiers
người chiến sĩ
for the homeland. My youthful spring, my father's love, my grandmother's
vì quê hương tuổi con Xuân bố Tình Yêu
affection, I
thương giống
put aside personal feelings. Homeland
bỏ tình riêng Quê
for homeland.
vì quê hương
[music]
[âm nhạc]
[Laughter] My
[Tiếng cười]
brothers, our country has changed,
các anh ơi đất nước mình đã đổi mới
our nation has been liberated, prosperous
dân tộc mình đã giải phóng ấm no
today. Coming to you, the
ngày hôm nay về bên anh những người
soldiers, living by the song, bowing their heads in gratitude,
chiến sĩ sống lời ca cúi đầu cảm tạ
regretting your loss. Those who long for
tiếc nuối các anh Những người mong muốn
peace, oh,
hòa vì
in the West,
ơi ở miền Tây
the soldiers
những người chiến sĩ
for the homeland,
vì quê hương
not knowing when, I
chẳng biết bao giờ
vow for all living beings,
nguyện vì chúng sinh
vowing to share hunger tonight.
nguyện cùng đói đêm nay
[music] The
[âm nhạc]
old battlefield has now become a blooming flower,
chiến trường xưa nay hóa thành hoa nở
buried deep, so that the trees and leaves can grow green. The whispering
bom đạn vùi sâu để cây lá lên xanh thì
voice of the earth still calls your names.
thầm tiếng đất vẫn gọi tên các anh Những
Immortal people, making the name of the Fatherland,
con người bất tử làm dạ danh Tổ quốc ơi
my homeland.  How
đừng quê hương tôi
grateful we are to the soldiers who, in
ơn biết mấy những người chiến sĩ
their youth, abandoned their love and
vì quê hương tuổi con Xuân bỏ tình yêu
affection for their
thương giống đò
homeland, leaving behind their romantic relationships to return home, bidding farewell and setting out for their country,
bỏ tình duyên về quê hương
sacrificing themselves
giã từ lên đường vì quê hương hy sinh
on the battlefield.
nơi chiến trường
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
Our country has been renewed,
đất nước mình đã đổi mới
our nation has been liberated, and we are prosperous
dân tộc mình đã giải phóng ấm no
today. We are with you, the
ngày hôm nay về bên anh những người
living soldiers, and we bow our heads in gratitude and
chiến sĩ sống người ta cúi đầu cảm tạ
regret. Those who wish for you,
tiếc nuối các anh Những người mong muốn
Hoa, to return. Oh, in the
Hoa đi
West,
Ôi ở miền Tây
the soldiers who,
những người chiến sĩ
for their homeland,
vì quê hương
didn't know the model of
chẳng biết mẫu
Nguyen Thi. The people of the West,
Nguyễn Thị chúng sinh
early in their lives, dedicated their lives and made heroic vows. They
sớm Hiến trọn đời
have come to double the screen. Oh, in the
nguyện hùng đã tới nhân đôi màn hình ta
Cloud region,
Ôi ở miền Mây
the soldiers
những người chiến sĩ
return home.
về quê hương
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
[Applause] We
[Vỗ tay]
pray with you,
nguyện cùng các anh
[Music]
[âm nhạc]